Nicolas Hery

New York, NY nicolahery@gmail.com http://nicolashery.com

Self-taught web developer with a background in applied mathematics and a thing for building well-designed web applications with great user experience that solve data-driven business problems or simply make people's lives better.

Experience

2010 -

Data Analyst

Present

FreshDirect, New York

- Designed and built a small web application that aggregates data from different systems and provides an interface allowing FreshDirect buyers to forecast product demand and replenish the warehouse
- · Led various ETL projects, acting as a "bridge" between IT and business users
- Wrote and implemented several Python scripts to transform and load data, as well as automate redundant tasks

Oct 2009 – Dec 2009

Student Project

Google, New York

- Managed a team of engineering students from Columbia University on a student Project for Google's Operations Research group
- Used Python and SimPy to simulate job scheduling in Google's data centers and optimize the algorithm to decrease power consumption

May 2009 – Jul 2009

Intern Consultant

Cylad Consulting, France

- Worked with a team of consultants for Airbus on the project planning of the Airbus 350 XWB
- Developed a Excel VBA tool to create Gantt charts from the main scheduling platform's data

May 2009 -Jun 2009

Freelance Consultant

Baby Speaking, France

- · Acted as a technology advisor for a multi-lingual child card startup
- Wrote a small PHP application used by international students applying for a job at Baby Seaking

Education

2009 - 2010

Columbia University

MS in Operations Research, New York

- Selected coursework: Deterministic and Stochastic Models, Corporate Finance, Entrepreneurship, Supply Chain
- Created a WordPress blog for the Entrepreneurship Club and published articles

2007 - 2009

Ecole Centrale de Nantes

MS in Industrial Engineering, France

• Selected coursework: Probability and Statistics, Calculus, Economics, International Strategy

Skills

Best at

JavaScript, Backbone.js, Python

Good at

HTML5, CSS3 (& Sass), Node is, MongoDB, MySQL, Photoshop

Influences

People

Paul Irish, Jeremy Ashkenas, Dan Shipper, Sacha Greif, Eric Ries

Products

Trello, 37signals, GitHub, LinkedIn Mobile, Square

Interests

web apps, design, user experience, data visualization, scientific computing, running, swimming, guitar, travelling, good wine, good scotch, good company